Guide to the Walter Francis White and Poppy Cannon Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1917-1955; Series I; 4.9 linear feet (14 boxes)
  - Walter White Correspondence
    - Sengstacke, John
    - Shaw, George Bernard
    - Singh, J. J.
      See: Indian League of America, Box 3, folder 96
    - "Sm - Sz" General (Box 6, Folder 191)
      To: 22 / From: 7
    - Smith, Lillian, 1945 November 7 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Snowden, Philip
    - Sorensen, Theodore C., 1949 December 27 (Box 6, Folder 193)
    - Southbury Training School, 1950 January 7-March 16 (Box 6, Folder 194)
      To: 7 / From: 5
    - Spingarn, Arthur B. (Arthur Barnett), 1928-1952, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 195)
    - Spingarn, Joel Elias, 1922 March 14, 1932 October 1, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 196)
    - Storey, Moorfield, 1923 May 18 (Box 6, Folder 197)
    - "Ta - Tz" General (Box 6, Folder 198)
    - Tubman, Mr. & Mrs. William V. S., 1954 December-1956 December (Box 6, Folder 199)
    - Tobias, Channing H., 1924-1954 (Box 6, Folder 200)
    - Town Hall of the Air, circa 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 201)
      To: 26 / From: 47
    - Trujillo, Rafael Molinas, 1950 (March 20)-Apr. n.d. (Box 6, Folder 202)
    - Truman, Harry S., 1948 December 9-1951 August 25, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 203)
      To: 10 / From: 17
    - Tully, Grace
      See: Franklin D. Roosevelt Foundation, Box 6, folder 181
    - "Ua - Uz" General (Box 7, Folder 204)
      To: 9 / From: 5
    - United States. Dept. of the Treasury (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - "Va - Vz" General (Box 7, Folder 206)
      To: 6 / From: 6
    - Van Doren, Carl and Mark, 1923 May 31, 1923 August 22, 1949 October 18 (Box 7, Folder 207)
      To: 3/ From: 0
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1926 February 12, 1942 December 4 (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - Viking Press, 1944-1955, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 209)
      To: 16 / From: 10
    - Virgin Islands, 1948, 1949, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - "Wa - Wh" General (Box 7, Folder 211)
      To: 32 / From: 15
    - Wagner, Robert F. (Robert Ferdinand) (Box 7, Folder 212)
    - Wallace, DeWitt
      See: Readers Digest, Box 6, folder 171
    - Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1944 December 7 (Box 7, Folder 213)
    - Wallas, Graham
    - Wallace, Herschel D., 1952 August 18 (Box 7, Folder 214)
    - Waring, J. Waties (Julius Waties) - Waties, Mrs. J., 1949 March 30-1950 April 14 (Box 7, Folder 215)
      To: 12 / From: 2
    - Waring, J. Waties (Julius Waties) - Waring, Mrs. J., 1949 July 18-1950 January 17 (Box 7, Folder 216)
      To: 8 / From: 4
    - Waring, J. Waties (Julius Waties) - Waring, Mrs. J., 1950-1956 (Box 7, Folder 217)
      To: 24 / From: 3
    - Webb, Sidney
    - Welles, Orson, 1946 October 17 (Box 7, Folder 218)
    - White, George [Father], n.d. (Box 7, Folder 219)
    - White, George [Brother], 1929-1935 (Box 7, Folder 220)
    - White, Gladys Powell, 1931-1945, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 221)
      To: 8 / From: 1
    - White, Gladys Powell, 1935-1936, 1943 October (Box 7, Folder 222)
    - White, Jane, 1952 June 20, 1953 October 6 (Box 7, Folder 223)
    - White, Madeleine, 1930 December 11 (Box 7, Folder 224)
    - White, Madeleine, 1931-1954, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 225)
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 226)
      To: 5 / From: 0
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 227)
      To: 17 / From: 0
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 228)
      To: 14 / From: 0
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 229)
      letter 1949 February 2 incomplete A.W. 9 Jan. 80
      To: 6 / From: 0
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 231)
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 232)
    - White Cannon, Poppy, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 233)
      To: 13 / From: 0
    - "Wi - Wz" General (Box 8, Folder 234)
    - Wilkins, Roy, 1945-1954 (Box 8, Folder 235)
      To: 17 / From: 3
    - Wilkins, Mrs. Roy, 1949 May 10 (Box 8, Folder 236)
    - Williams, Chester S. (Chester Sidney)
      See: Town Hall of the Air, Box 6, folder 201
    - Wirth, Louis
      See: American Council on Race Relations, Box 1, folder 6
    - Wood, Clement, 1934 March 24, 26 (Box 8, Folder 237)
    - Wright, Louis T. (Louis Tompkins), 1937-1952, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 238)
    - "X,Y,Z" General (Box 8, Folder 239)
    - Zanuck, Darryl Francis, 1949 November 1-December 5 (Box 8, Folder 240)
    - Zephirin, Mauclair, 1952-1953, 1955 March 4 (Box 8, Folder 241)
    - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 242)
      To: 22 / From: 2
    - Unidentified (Box 8, Folder 243)
      To: 18 / From: 0
    - Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 244)
  - Poppy Cannon Correspondence
    Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
    The correspondence of Poppy Cannon is organized under two headings: General Correspondence and Letters of Condolence. Letters addressed jointly to Poppy Cannon and Walter White are filed with the Walter White Correspondence.
    In general, the material may be said to fall into the following groupings:
    1. 1945-1950
    The correspondence falling within these dates is almost exclusively that of Walter White with Poppy Cannon. It includes much during 1948-1949 on their marriage and personal plans, but it also covers other subjects, such as collaboration on a play, blacks in motion pictures, the N.A.A.C.P., and White's activities and relations with the Association.
    2. 1951-1954
    The correspondence falling within these dates is the most general in character, covering a variety of Poppy Cannon's interests. Subjects touched upon in this grouping include cooking, public relations work for Haiti, and the personal and public activities in which she and White were involved. The correspondence between White and Poppy Cannon in this section is small.
    3. 1955-1956
    The correspondence falling within these dates generally relates to the publication arrangements for Walter White's last book, How Far The Promised Land, and Poppy Cannon's memoir of White, A Gentle Knight.
    - General Correspondence, 1945-1956
    - "Aa - Az" General (Box 9, Folder 1)
      To: 14 / From: 5
    - Abrams, Charles, 1955 March 22, 1956 March 13 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Ankarcrona, Elsrig, 1950-1955, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Askland, Alf, 1952-1956, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 4)
      To: 30 / From: 6
    - Askland, Alf, 1952 June 4-November 26, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Askland, Alf, 1951-1955, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 6)
      To: 45 / From: 5
    - Askland, Alf (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - "Ba-Bz" General (Box 9, Folder 8)
      To: 31 / From: 4
    - Baldwin, Faith, [circa 1955] (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Benton, William, 1955 March 28, [December] (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Black, Algernon D. (Algernon David), 1955 October 20-1956 October 24, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 11)
      Includes copy of letter from Roy Wilkins dated 1956 May 22
    - Branch, Bobbie, 1952 June 20 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Brewer, William M., 1955 Aug 29 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson) and Jane, 1955 Dec 12-1956 Sep 19, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      To: 29 / From: 4
    - "Ca - Cz" General (Box 9, Folder 15)
      To: 6 / From: 4
    - Cannon, Cynthia, 1948-1955, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      To: 26 / From: 3
    - Cannon, Cynthia, 1950, 1952, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Cannon, Cynthia, 1952, 1953, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Cassagnol, Edouard
      See: Series I, Walter White Correspondence
    - Christmas Card List, 1949, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Cousins, Norman, 1947-1956 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - "Da - Dz, Ea - Ez" General (Box 9, Folder 21)
      To: 20 / From: 6
    - Dulles, Allen Welsh, 1955 November 9-December 3 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1954 April 21-1956 October 13 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Estimé, Dumarsais, 1949 October 20 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - "Fa - Fz, Ga - Gz" General (Box 9, Folder 25)
      To: 30 / From: 8
    - Gannett, Lewis S., 1956 October 2, October 21 n.d. (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Garrison, Lloyd K. (Lloyd Kirkham), 1955 March 22 (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Glenn, Alice White, 1955 March 30 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Graham, Nancy, 1954 May 17, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Gruskin, Henrietta, 1950, 1951, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 30)
      mother of Poppy Cannon
    - "Ha - Hz" General (Box 10, Folder 31)
      To: 29 / From: 10
    - Haiti
      - de Catalogne, Gerard, 1953 January 1-1955 March 8 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - de Catalogne, Gerard, 1951 December 6-1952 December 30 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - Chauvet, Ernest, 1952-1955 (Box 10, Folder 34)
        To: 5 / From: 19
      - Chauvet, Pierre, 1951-1955, n.d.
      - Dumond, Jules, 1952 January 16-1953 March 7 (Box 10, Folder 35)
        To: 9 / From: 7
      - Duyon, M. Guy, 1952 February 25-December 3, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 36)
        To: 14 / From: 19
      - Duyon, M. Guy, 1952 December 5-1953 June 8, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 37)
        To: 15 / From: 18
      - Foche, Luc E., 1951 September 17-December 4 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - Laraque, Guy F., 1952 August 29-1953 April 27 (Box 10, Folder 39)
      - Magloire, Paul Eugène, 1951-1956, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 40)
        To: 4 / From: 5
      - Magloire Reception, [circa 1955 January] (Box 10, Folder 41)
      - Zephirin, Mauclair, 1952-1955 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Hammerstein, Oscar, 1952-1955, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell) and Marie, 1952-1956 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Hastie, William H., 1947 November 10 (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Hill, Herbert, 1955 November 2 (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Peter Hilton Inc., 1948-1955 (Box 10, Folder 47)
    - Hoffman, Henry, 1955 June 8-1956 September 10 (Box 10, Folder 48)
      To: 7 / From: 2
    - Huggins, Molly, 1955 June 19-1956 January 21, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 49)
    - Hughes, Langston, 1956 October 20-24 (Box 10, Folder 50)
    - "I, Ja - Jz" General (Box 10, Folder 51)
      To: 13 / From: 3
    - Jackson, Mabel Dodge, 1949-1955 (Box 10, Folder 52)
    - Johnson, Georgia Douglas Camp, 1955 April 4-1956 December 20 (Box 10, Folder 53)
    - Johnson Publishing Company, 1952 January-July, 1955 November 7 (Box 10, Folder 54)
    - Jones, Madison S., 1945-1956 (Box 10, Folder 55)
    - "Ka - Kz, La - Lz" General (Box 10, Folder 56)
      To: 31 / From: 9
    - Kaplan, Kivie, 1955 March 25-1956 December 10 (Box 10, Folder 57)
    - Kefauver, Estes, 1953, 1955, (1956) (Box 10, Folder 58)
      To: 3 / From: 2
    - Legal Papers, 1949-1950 (Box 10, Folder 59)
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1956 January 12 (Box 10, Folder 60)
    - "Ma - Mz" General (Box 10, Folder 61)
    - Magloire, Paul Eugène
      See: Haiti, Box 10, folders 32-42
    - Marshall, Thurgood and Mrs. Marshall, 1948 November 18, 1955 October 27 (Box 10, Folder 62)
    - Martin, Helen and Eugene
    - McBride, Mary Margaret, 1949 April 22, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 63)
    - Mitchell, Clarence, 1953-1956 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Moon, Henry Lee, 1953-1956, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Morse, William, 1956 September 12, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 66)
    - Murrow, Edward R., 1954 October 1-1955 November 9, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 67)
    - "Na - Nz" General (Box 11, Folder 68)
      To: 20 / From: 9
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1955 June 4-1956 August 28 (Box 11, Folder 69)
      To: 22 / From: 8
    - Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1954 November 23, 1956 October 2, 12 (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1955 March 4-1956 October 2 (Box 11, Folder 71)
      To: 5 / From: 5
    - Nunn, William Goldwin, 1956 October 24 (Box 11, Folder 72)
    - "Oa - Oz, Pa - Pz, Qa - Qz" General (Box 11, Folder 73)
      To: 18 / From: 5
    - Oram, Harold L., 1955 October 12-1955 December 12 (Box 11, Folder 74)
    - Pandit, Vijaya Lakshmi, 1947-1955, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 75)
      To: 12 / From: 8
    - Paton, Alan, 1955 March 26, 1955 December 12 (Box 11, Folder 76)
    - Philippe, Charles Claudius, 1948-1956, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 77)
      To: 23 / From: 1
    - Philippe, Claudia, 1951-1956, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 78)
      To: 18 / From: 3
    - Philippe, Claudia, correspondence with Alf Askland and Cynthia Cannon, 1951-1955, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Philippe, Claudia, (1951) 1953-1956, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - Pike, James A. (James Albert), 1955 November 15, November 23 (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Poems, undated (Box 11, Folder 82)
      See also: Poems, drafts, typescript and typescript carbon.
    - Powell, Adam Clayton, Jr., 1955 March 24-1956 October 2 (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - "Ra - Rz" General (Box 11, Folder 84)
      To: 19 / From: 8
    - Randolph, A. Philip (Asa Philip), 1956 June 8 (Box 11, Folder 85)
    - Readers Digest, 1947-1956, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 86)
    - Reid, Helen Rogers, 1952-1956 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - Rinehart & Company, Inc., 1955-1957, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1955 January 3 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1950 August 4, 1955-1956, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - Roper, Elmo, 1955 April 7, 1955 November 15 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - "Sa - Sz" General (Box 11, Folder 92)
      To: 35 / From: 5
    - Singh, J. J. and Malti, 1953 March 4, 1953 March 7, 1955 October 12, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - Spingarn, Arthur B. (Arthur Barnett) and Spingarn, Mrs. Joel E., 1955 October 17, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - "Ta - Tz" General (Box 11, Folder 95)
      To: 8 / From: 2
    - Tillman, Nathaniel Patrick, 1956-12-19; 1961-08-03 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Tobias, Channing H., 1953 February 28-1953 March 25, 1955 April 8-1955 December 14 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Toklas, Alice B., 1954 June 29-1956 December 11, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 98)
      To: 9 / From: 1
    - Truman, Harry S., 1950-1956 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - "Ua - Uz, Va - Vz" General (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Van Vechten, Carl, 1955 October 15-1956 October 24 (Box 11, Folder 101)
    - Viking Press, 1955 March 22-1956 October 31 (Box 11, Folder 102)
    - "Wa - Wz, Z" General (Box 11, Folder 103)
      To: 36 / From: 11
    - Wallace, DeWitt
      See: Readers Digest, Box 11, folder 86a
    - Waring, Julius Waties, Mrs. Waring
    - Weaver, Robert, 1955 September 5 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Wesley, Charles H. (Charles Harris), 1956 February 29 (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - White, Madeleine, 1949-1956, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 106)
      To: 35 / From: 7
    - White, Walter, 1945 September 10-December 3, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 107)
    - White, Walter, 1946 March 27-December 31, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 108)
      Includes copies of letters sent to Walter White from Langston Hughes (1946 July 27), Eleanor Roosevelt (1946 July 25), and Arthur B. Spingarn (1946 July 25).
    - White, Walter, 1947 January 10-October 31 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    - White, Walter, 1947 November 1-December 20 (Box 12, Folder 110)
      Includes copies of letters from William H. Hastie dated 1947 November-December
      To: 15 / From: 9
    - White, Walter, 1948 September 20-October 11, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 111)
    - White, Walter, 1949 January 2-February 11 (Box 12, Folder 112)
      To: 29 / From: 0
    - White, Walter, 1949 February 12-December 2 n.d. (Box 12, Folder 113)
      To: 22 / From: 0
    - White, Walter, 1950 February 19-1954 April 16, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 114)
      To: 27 / From: 0
    - Wilkins, Roy, 1955 March 31-1956 June 14, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 115)
    - Williams, Robert J., 1955 July 27-1956 August 30 (Box 12, Folder 116)
      To: 11 / From: 5
    - Wright, Louis T. (Louis Tompkins), n.d. (Box 12, Folder 117)
    - Unidentified (Box 12, Folder 118)
      To: 21 / From: 3
    - Unidentified (Box 12, Folder 119)
      To: 41 / From: 1
  - Letters of Condolence
    - Aa - Az, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - Ba - Bz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    - Ca - Cz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    - Da - Dz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - Ea - Ez, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 124)
    - Fa - Fz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 125)
    - Ga - Gz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 126)
    - Ha - Hz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 127)
    - Ia - Iz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 128)
    - Ja - Jz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 129)
    - Ka - Kz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 130)
    - La - Lz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 131)
    - Ma - Mh, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 132)
    - Mi - Mz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 133)
    - Na - Nz, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 134)
    - N.A.A.C.P., 1956 (Box 13, Folder 135)
    - Oa - Oz, Pa - Pz, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 136)
    - Ra - Rz, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 137)
    - Sa - Sn, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 138)
    - Sp - Sz, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 139)
    - Ta - Tz, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 140)
    - Ua - Uz, Va - Vz, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 141)
    - Wa - Wz, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 142)
    - X, Y, Z, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - Miscellaneous, 1956 (Box 14, Folder 144)
- Writings, 1921-1958; Series II; 7.09 linear feet (18 boxes)
  The series is organized into two subseries: Walter White and Poppy Cannon.
  The series documents Walter White's career as a writer (including work as a war correspondent) and as the Secretary for the N.A.A.C.P. spanning the dates 1921 to 1955. The series also documents Poppy Cannon's career as a writer and as a publicist for the Republic of Haiti spanning the dates 1930 to1958. The series contains drafts, background materials, publicity materials, correspondence, and reviews.
  - Walter White
    The subseries is organized under the following headings: Major Works, Articles, Lectures, Broadcasts, Short Stories, Book Reviews, Other Writings, and Writings of Others.
    - Major Works
      - The Fire in the Flint
        - Draft, chapters 1-9 and 22, typescript and holograph, corrected, Before 1924 (Box 15, Folder 145-146)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, Before 1924
        - Dramatization, typescript, corrected, 1925 (Box 15, Folder 147)
          See also: Mason, Peter, "The Fire in the Flint: A Drama in Three Acts", typescript carbon.
          Written with George M. Widder
      - Flight
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, Before 1926 (Box 15, Folder 148-150)
        - Galley proofs, corrected, Before 1926
        - Page proofs, corrected, Before 1926
      - How Far the Promised Land?
        See also: "How Far Off is the Revolution?", notes and draft fragment, typescript.
        - Chapter outlines, typescript and holograph, Before 1955 (Box 16, Folder 151-152)
        - Draft, typescript and carbon, corrected, Before 1955 (Box 16, Folder 153-156)
        - Publicity, 1955 (Box 16, Folder 157)
      - A Man Called White
        - Draft fragment, episodes A-H, typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1948 (Box 17, Folder 158)
        - Draft fragment, typescript carbon, corrected, Before 1948 (Box 17, Folder 159-164)
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, Before 1948 (Box 18, Folder 165-172)
        - Final draft, typescript carbon, Before 1948 (Box 19, Folder 173-180)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, Before 1948 (Box 20, Folder 181-185)
      - Rope and Faggot: A Biography of Judge Lynch
        - Draft, chapters 1-3, typescript and typescript carbon corrected, 1928 March 25 (Box 20, Folder 186)
        - Draft, chapters 1-5 and 8-10, typescript carbon, circa 1928 (Box 20, Folder 187)
        - Setting typescript, corrected, 1928 (Box 21, Folder 188-190)
        - Page proofs, corrected, circa 1928
    - Articles
      - "America's Past and Future Linked to Haiti", draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 22, Folder 191)
      - "Are the Democrats Losing the Negro Vote?", draft, typescript, undated (Box 22, Folder 192)
      - "50 Years of Fighting for Civil Rights", outline and draft, typescript, 1950 January 10 (Box 22, Folder 193)
      - "Can Democracy Solve the Race Problem", draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 22, Folder 194)
      - Chicago Defender articles, drafts, typescript, typescript carbon, and holograph, 1949-1952 (Box 22, Folder 195-200)
      - "Color Line Around the World", outline and drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 22, Folder 201)
        Written with Poppy Cannon
      - "Development of Technique of Lynching", drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 22, Folder 202)
      - "Filming a Skid Row", draft fragment, typescript carbon, undated (Box 22, Folder 203)
      - Graphic Syndicate articles, drafts, typescript, typescript carbon, and holograph, 1947-1950 (Box 22, Folder 204-206)
      - Graphic Syndicate articles, drafts, typescript, typescript carbon, and holograph, 1947-1950 (Box 23, Folder 207-216)
      - "How Far Off is the Revolution?", notes and draft fragment, typescript, undated (Box 24, Folder 217)
        See also: How Far the Promised Land?.
      - "I Confess", draft, typescript, circa 1926 (Box 24, Folder 218)
      - "Is the Negro Returning to the Republican Party?", draft, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 219)
      - "The Menace of Segregation", draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 24, Folder 220)
      - "My Father's Death", notes and drafts, typescript, corrected, 1942 (Box 24, Folder 221)
      - New York Post
        - Background materials and notes, 1944-1945 (Box 24, Folder 222-227)
        - Articles, drafts, holograph, typescript, and typescript carbon, 1944-1945 (Box 24, Folder 228)
      - "Pan-Africa", draft, typescript, corrected, 1921 October (Box 24, Folder 229)
        Accompanied by reports "To the Board Re: English Committee on Lynching" and "The Second Pan-African Congress." Presented to N.A.A.C.P. upon return from the Pan-African Congress
      - "Paul Robeson: Right or Wrong?", drafts, holograph, typescript, typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 230)
      - The Presidential Election of 1952, draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1952 (Box 24, Folder 231)
      - "Sojourner Truth", draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 24, Folder 232)
      - "What Can I Do?", drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 233)
      - "What You Can Do in Times of Tension", draft, typescript carbon, undated (Box 24, Folder 234)
      - "Who Is Colored and What Does Being Colored Mean?", outline and drafts, typescript and typescript carbon, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 235)
    - Lectures
      - Address at the Closing Session of the 42nd Annual Convention of the N.A.A.C.P., drafts, typescript, 1942 July 1 (Box 25, Folder 236)
      - Address at the Wartime Conference, draft, typescript, 1944 July 16 (Box 25, Folder 237)
      - "How Much Democracy Can the Negro Expect?", Commencement Address at Fisk University, draft, typescript carbon, 1941 July 2 (Box 25, Folder 238)
      - Introductory Statement on the Occasion of the Presentation of Petition to the United Nations, draft, typescript, 1947 October 23 (Box 25, Folder 239)
      - Lecture tour itineraries, notes, and correspondence, 1948-1949 (Box 25, Folder 240-241)
      - Remarks Before the Fourth Annual Conference on Civil Liberties, draft excerpts, typescript, 1951 March 1 (Box 25, Folder 242)
      - Remarks to the New Jersey CIO, draft excerpts, typescript, 1952 September 7 (Box 25, Folder 243)
      - Untitled, incomplete draft, holograph, undated (Box 25, Folder 244)
        Discusses reaction to West coast lecture tour
    - Broadcasts
      - Comment on the 1952 Presidential Campaign, draft, typescript, corrected, 1952 August 8 (Box 25, Folder 245)
      - Comment on Daniel Francois Malan for WLIB (New York), draft, typescript, corrected, 1952 August (Box 25, Folder 246)
      - Current Events in Mississippi for WLIB, draft, holograph, corrected, 1954 December 15 (Box 25, Folder 247)
      - "Does the Veto Menace the United Nations?" for CBS, drafts, typescript carbon, corrected, 1946 June 20 (Box 25, Folder 248)
      - Interview with Charles Abrams for WLIB, topics for discussion draft, typescript, corrected, 1955 March 17 (Box 25, Folder 249)
      - Interview with Roy Tasco Davis, United States Ambassador to Haiti, for WLIB, draft discussion topics, typescript, undated (Box 25, Folder 250)